<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE container [
<!ENTITY hellip     " &#x2E;&#xA0;&#x2E;&#xA0;&#x2E; ">
<!ENTITY inked     "&#x2759;">
<!ENTITY caret     "&#x2038;">
<!ENTITY minus     "&#x2212;">
<!ENTITY plus     "&#x002B;">
<!ENTITY shy     "&#x00AD;">
<!ENTITY sigrange     "&#x002D;">
<!ENTITY swdash     "&#x2002;&#x007E;&#x2002;">
<!ENTITY verbar     "&#x2002;&#x007C;&#x2002;">
<!ENTITY cmacr     "&#x63;&#x304;">
]>

<container xmlns="http://www.mla.org/NVSns">
    
    
    
    <div type="appendix" xml:id="div_appendix">
        
        
        <p>The Antipholuses are treated differently. They are hardly ever distinguished, as for
            example on H2<hi rend="superscript">vb</hi>, where Compositor C sets 17 <hi rend="italic"
                >S. Dro.</hi>s and 14 <hi rend="italic">Ant.</hi>s (plus 1 <hi rend="italic"
                    >Antiph.</hi>, 1 <hi rend="italic">Anti.</hi>, and 2 <hi rend="italic">An.</hi> in a
            full line and a catchword). Only in Act 5, when at <ref targType="lb" target="#tln_1820"
                >1820</ref> the brothers start appearing together, does Compositor B, or the copy,
            consistently identify them.</p>
        
        <p><ref targType="bibl" target="#b_scom1982"><name type="app">Scott</name></ref> (1982,
            pp. 2–4): <quote>Egeon in the first scene is a pathetic old man, isolated in an alien
                land divorced from wife and children through the dictates of wealth and Fortune:
                [quotes <ref targType="lb" target="#tln_0040" targetEnd="#tln_0047">40–7</ref>]. [<hi
                    rend="italic">3</hi>] This incident was eventually to isolate Egeon from his wife
                and children so that now in Ephesus he has no will to live, his only wish being to
                know whether his family are still alive: [quotes <ref targType="lb" target="#tln_0140"
                    targetEnd="#tln_0142">140–2</ref>, <ref targType="lb" target="#tln_0160"
                        targetEnd="#tln_0161">160–1</ref>]. The <quote>procrastination</quote> of his death
                implies that Egeon has spent the last five years, at least, of his life in the despair
                of isolation, searching for his family, his roots which are his identity. It is this
                loss of self-identity not only for Egeon, but for all his relations which is to form
                the kernel of the play; a simple idea at first only proposed by the old man’s pathetic
                tale but soon stated explicitly as a theme, by Antipholus of Syracuse: [quotes <ref
                    targType="lb" target="#tln_0199" targetEnd="#tln_0204">199–204</ref>]. It is
                misleading to see this statement as an insight to Antipholus’s characterization. We
                are not watching a comedy dealing in such terms but rather a farce which negates
                characterization in favour of simple archetype. Antipholus’s speech therefore
                naturally becomes a clarification of Egeon’s opening [<hi rend="italic">4</hi>]
                statement.&hellip;Thus Egeon’s exposition is simply clarified by Antipholus before we
                are presented with the complexities of the variations, which in this case we call the
                <quote>errors</quote> on the theme of the loss of identity. We soon find therefore
                that the three principal characters, Antipholus of Syracuse, Antipholus of Ephesus,
                and Adriana are comically portrayed as separated from any relationship with another
                person. All are searching, striving, enquiring and yet getting nowhere since there
                seem to be no answers.</quote> Such <quote>depiction of separation and utter
                    loneliness has found expression in the farcical theatre of the absurd.</quote></p>        
        
        
    </div>
    
    
</container>
